Guide to the Time Inc. Time Editorial Records 1938-2009 MS 3009-RG 7
New-York Historical Society
- Series III.A. Art Department: Cover Researcher Rosemary Frank Files, 1948-2009 (bulk 1963-1988); 20 Linear feet in 20 record cartons
  - Subseries III.A.2. Artist Files, 1948-2009 (bulk 1963-1988); 18 Linear feet in 18 record cartons
    - Upshur, Thomas (Offsite-box 862, Folder 42)
    - Valeska, Lizallota (Offsite-box 862, Folder 43)
    - Valla, Victor R. (Offsite-box 862, Folder 44)
    - Vandivert, William (Offsite-box 862, Folder 45)
    - Van Dongen, Kees (Offsite-box 862, Folder 46)
    - Van Haeydonck, Paul (Offsite-box 862, Folder 47)
    - Varga, Arnold (Offsite-box 862, Folder 48)
    - Velanco, Leandro (Offsite-box 862, Folder 49)
    - Velde, Robert (Offsite-box 862, Folder 50)
    - Veno, Joe (Offsite-box 862, Folder 51)
    - Vickrey, Robert (Offsite-box 862, Folder 52-53)
    - Victor, Jim (Offsite-box 862, Folder 54)
    - Vidal-Quadras, Alejo (Offsite-box 862, Folder 55)
    - Vietnam War Artist (Offsite-box 862, Folder 56)
    - Vietor, Dean (Offsite-box 862, Folder 57)
    - Von Ringelheim, Paul (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 1)
    - Vuchinich, Vuk (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 2)
    - Wadsworth, Pat (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 3)
    - Wald, Carol (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 4)
    - Waghorn, Kerry (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 5)
    - Walker, Gil (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 6)
    - Warhol, Andy (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 7)
    - Wasserman, Norma (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 8)
    - Weaver, Robert (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 9)
    - Weiner, Leslie (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 10)
    - Weiss, Edward H. (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 11)
    - Weller, Don (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 12)
    - Wells, Charles (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 13)
    - Werden, Donald (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 14)
    - Wesselmann, Tom (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 15)
    - Wheeler, Dennis (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 16)
    - White, Charles, III (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 17)
    - Whiteley, Brett (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 18)
    - Wicks, Alden (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 19)
    - Wiegard, Richard (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 20)
    - Wiley, William (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 21)
    - Wilkison, David (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 22)
    - Williams, Oliver (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 23-24)
    - Williams, Paul (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 25)
    - Wilk, J. Anthony (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 26)
    - Wilson, John H. (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 27)
    - Wilson, Rowland B. (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 28)
    - Wilson, Wes (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 29)
    - Wisdom, Leon (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 30)
    - Witte, Mike (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 31)
    - Wittrup, Jack (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 32)
    - Woell, J. Fred (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 33)
    - Wolf, Sherry (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 34)
    - Woltersdorf (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 35)
    - Wong, Timothy (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 36)
    - Wood, Grant (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 37)
    - Wood-Thomas, Alan (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 38)
    - Wright, Don (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 39)
    - Wulp, John (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 40)
    - Wybrants-Lynch, Sharon (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 41)
    - Wyeth, Andrew (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 42)
    - Wyeth, James (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 43)
    - Wyeth, James [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R39)
    - Wyeth Hurd, Henriette (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 44)
    - Xaras, Theodore (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 45)
    - Yates, Graem (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 46)
    - Yerkes, Lane (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 47)
    - Yokoo, Tadanori (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 48)
    - Yoors, Jan (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 49)
    - Zaid, Barry (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 50)
    - Zagorski, Stanislaw (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 51)
    - Zeitlin, Harriet [Mrs. David I.] (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 52)
    - Zekowski, Marilyn (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 53)
    - Ziegler, Laura (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 54)
    - Ziering, Bob (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 55)
    - Zimmerman, John (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 56)
    - Zuka (Mrs. Louis Mittelberg) (Offsite-box 2588, Folder 57)
- Series III.B. Art Department: Senior Design Coordinator Linda Freeman Files, 1965, 1989-2000; 0.5 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  Linda Freeman's files include include records documenting expenses related to the creation of magazine covers and the history of the logo and the magazine. Some materials are from Art Director Rudolph "Rudy" Hoglund.
  - Contracts: Legal - Meetings, 1989-1990 (Offsite-box 3293, Folder 25)
  - Contracts: Legal - Meetings [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R39)
  - Contracts: Old Variations [RESTRICTED], circa 1989 (Offsite-box R39)
  - Contracts: Work for Hire and Cover Photo Assessment [RESTRICTED], 1989; 0.5 Linear feet (2 boxes) (Offsite-box R39)
  - Cover Expenses, 1997 (Offsite-box 3293, Folder 26)
  - History of Time, 2000 (Offsite-box 3293, Folder 27)
  - History of Time Logo, 1965, 1991 (Offsite-box 3293, Folder 28)
  - Transparencies of Artwork, circa 1997 (Offsite-box 3293, Folder 29)
- Series III.C. Art Department: Cover Carbon Files, 1960-1972; 3 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
  Carbon Files were created by reporters and researchers for every article that ran in a Time Inc. magazine, or in this case every cover created, comprising all the collected research, and retained by that magazine for around 14 months before being turned over to the library and archives.
  Cover Carbon Files include correspondence from the Art Department to Time Editorial staff Edward Jamieson, James Keough, and Henry Grunwald, Time Publishing staff, and Time News Service staff. Besides longtime cover researcher and curator of the Time cover collection Rosemary Frank, Art Department staff represented include Nancy Atkinson who may have been Frank's predecessor, and cover researcher Nancy Faber.
  Research includes memoranda reporting on statements from the artists (Warhol on his Jane Fonda cover); descriptions of the medium used; color descriptions on the subjects to accompany black-and-white photographs; and correspondence with non-artists to acquire photograph props (hospital for a patient bill; police department for firearms). 1970s files have some information on gifting the cover collection to the National Portrait Gallery.
  The general files are organized chronologically with one specific file at the end.
  - Carbon Files, 1960-1963 (Offsite-box 2560)
  - Carbon Files, 1963-1969 (Offsite-box 2561)
  - Carbon Files, 1967-1972 (Offsite-box 2562, Folder 1-10)
  - Carbon Files: Rothschild Cover, 1963 (Offsite-box 2562, Folder 11)
- Series IV. Rosalind Constable Reports, 1948-1967; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  The reports of Time journalist Rosalind Constable began as an experiment to find content for Time and Life. The stated intent was to comment "[On] the contents of the highbrow magazines of England, France and America..." with the first report entitled "Weekly Reports from the Cultural Front." Constable's purview quickly expanded to include publications from and about other countries. The number of magazines reviewed for content were vast and included Sight and Sound, La Table Ronde, The Kenyon Review, Horizon, The Cornhill, Dublin Review and Japan Quarterly.
  The Rosalind Constable Reports include her weekly reports about cultural affairs and the avant-garde art scene as covered by "the little magazines." Constable wrote on theatre, film, literature, poetry, and art, but also philosophy and intellectualism, and strayed at times into the cultural impact of "bloodsports" and business topics. Examples of report titles include "Science Fiction and the French," "Trends in English Poetry," "The New Religion of Art," and "Democracy is Out." Her later reports include lists of selected New York City cultural events. Also included are memoranda regarding reactions to her reports, requests for specific topics, and publishing statistics.
  - Reports, 1948-1957 (Offsite-box 621)
  - Reports, 1958-1967 (Offsite-box 622)
- Series V. Letters Department, 1938-1998; 9.5 Linear feet in 8 record cartons and 1 microfilm box including 8 reels of microfilm
  Letters Department Records include files preparing reader letters for publication and microfilm containing summaries of reader letters and lists of known errors from the Letters section.
  Organized into three subseries:
  Subseries V.A. Published Letters Files
  Subseries V.B. Reports
  Subseries V.C. Scrapbook: Stories on Women's Issues
  - Subseries V.A. Published Letters Files, 1994-1998; 6 Linear feet in 6 record cartons
    Published Letter Files have materials created in preparation for publishing reader letters in each issue including lists of published letters, galley proofs, and originals of reader letters that were sent in via AOL posts, fax, and mail. The files may be from Letters Editor Betty Satterwhite.
    Organized chronologically by magazine issue date.
    - Published Letters, 1994 October 3 - December 12 (Offsite-box 2685)
    - Published Letters, 1994 December 19 - 1995 March 27 (Offsite-box 2686)
    - Published Letters, 1995 April 3 - 24 (Offsite-box 2687, Folder 1-4)
    - Published Letters, 1995 September 11 - November 27 (Offsite-box 3243)
    - Published Letters, 1995 December 4 - 1996 March 25 (Offsite-box 3244)
    - Published Letters, 1996 April 1 - May 27 (Offsite-box 3245)
    - Published Letters, 1998 March 2 - April 27 (Offsite-box 2687, Folder 5-13)
    - Published Letters, 1998 May 4 - July 20 (Offsite-box 2688)
    - Published Letters, 1998 July 21 - October 19 (Offsite-box 2689)
    - Published Letters, 1998 October 26 - December 21 (Offsite-box 2690)
  - Subseries V.B. Reports, 1938-1980; 0.5 Linear feet in 1 microfilm box including 8 reels of microfilm
    Letters Department reports include summaries of reader letters to Time and lists of known errors. All reports in this series on available on microfilm only. All dates refer to the contents, not date of imaging. Indexes for the reels included.
    - Time Letters Department Reports, 1938 January-1948 August (Box 2349, Reel 1)
    - Time Letters Department Reports, 1948 September-1950 December (Box 2349, Reel 2)
    - Time Letters Department Reports, 1951 January-1958 September (Box 2349, Reel 3)
    - Time Letters Department Reports, 1958 October-1963 May (Box 2349, Reel 4)
    - Time Letters Department Reports, 1963 June-1965 February (Box 2349, Reel 5)
    - Time Letters Department Reports, 1965 March-1969 April (Box 2349, Reel 6)
    - Time Letters Department Reports, 1969 May-1974 March (Box 2349, Reel 7)
    - Time Letters Department Reports, 1974 April-1980 December (Box 2349, Reel 8)
  - Subseries ___. Scrapbooks: published letters to the editor -- RECOMMENDED FOR DEACCESSION, 1928-1965, 1974-1981; 8 Linear feet (8 boxes)
    Includes scrapbooks with clippings from Time of published letters to the editor. The condition is terrible and the archival value is low since these are magazine clippings of published letters to the editor. The letters are still available in better condition in the magazine run.
  - Subseries V.C. Scrapbook: Stories on Women's Issues, 1930-1941; 0.2 Linear feet in 1 oversize folder
    This scrapbook was probably compiled by the Letters Department and contains clippings of stories about women. The clippings may be from Time as similar scrapbooks have been found containing clippings of the letters to the editor.
    - Scrapbook, 1930-1941; 0.2 Linear feet in 1 oversize folder (Offsite-box 3081)
- Series VI. Elections Research, 1964-1985; 6 Linear feet in 6 record cartons
  Elections Research contains reporting by Time Life News Service on United States presidential nominee conventions and commissioned public opinion surveys focusing on candidates, politics, and elections. The surveys include the full tabulated results and memoranda reports analyzing and summarizing the results.
  While it is not clear who at Time collected and compiled these materials, some reports are addressed to Assistant Managing Editor Richard Duncan. The firm conducting the surveys was Daniel Yankelovich, Inc., later renamed Yankelovich, Skelly, & White, Inc. (Yankelovich). Some reports are jointly from Yankelovich and the Time Policy Planning Group. Some reports state they are for Time Soundings, maybe referring to a magazine section.
  Topics covered by the surveys include social resentment indicator, past voting record, main issues of concern, impressions of prominent people, and opinions on contemporary political and social issues.
  - News Service Coverage: Republican Convention, 1964 (Offsite-box 2769, Folder 1)
  - News Service Coverage: Democratic Convention, 1968 (Offsite-box 2769, Folder 2-3)
  - News Service Coverage: Republican Convention, 1968 (Offsite-box 2769, Folder 4-5)
  - News Service Coverage: Democratic Convention, 1976 (Offsite-box 2769, Folder 6)
  - News Service Coverage: Republican Convention, 1976 (Offsite-box 2769, Folder 7)
  - News Service Coverage: Republican Convention, 1976 (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 1-2)
  - Report: Time Panel, 1972? (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 3)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1972 September (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 4)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1976 May (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 5-6)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1976 June (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 7)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1976 October (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 8)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1978 June (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 9)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1979 October (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 10)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1979 December (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 11)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1980 January (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 12)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1980 April (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 13)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1980 September (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 14)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1980 October (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 15)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1981 January (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 16)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1981 May (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 17)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1982 March (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 18)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1982 June (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 19)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1982 October (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 20)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1982 December (Offsite-box 2770, Folder 21)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1983 March (Offsite-box 2771, Folder 1)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1983 July (Offsite-box 2771, Folder 2)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1984 August (Offsite-box 2771, Folder 3)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1984 September (Offsite-box 2771, Folder 4)
  - Yankelovich: Report [empty], 1984 October (Offsite-box 2771, Folder 5)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1984 December (Offsite-box 2771, Folder 6)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1985 July (Offsite-box 2771, Folder 7)
  - Yankelovich: Report, 1985 July-August (Offsite-box 2771, Folder 8)
  - Yankelovich: Study, 1972 (Offsite-box 2771, Folder 9)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Fact Sheet, 1976 (Offsite-box 2771, Folder 10)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, 1972 September (Offsite-box 2771, Folder 11-12)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, 1972 October (Offsite-box 2771, Folder 13-14)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, 1976 (Offsite-box 2771, Folder 15-18)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, 1976? (Offsite-box 2772, Folder 1-2)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, after 1977 (Offsite-box 2772, Folder 3)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, 1979 August (Offsite-box 2772, Folder 4)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, 1980 (Offsite-box 2772, Folder 5-7)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, 1980 January (Offsite-box 2772, Folder 8-9)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, 1980 March (Offsite-box 2773, Folder 1)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, 1980 April (Offsite-box 2773, Folder 2)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, 1980 May (Offsite-box 2773, Folder 3)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, 1980 September (Offsite-box 2773, Folder 4-5)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, 1980 October (Offsite-box 2773, Folder 6)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, 1981 January (Offsite-box 2773, Folder 7-8)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, 1981 May (Offsite-box 2774, Folder 1-2)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, 1982 March (Offsite-box 2774, Folder 3-4)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, 1982 June (Offsite-box 2774, Folder 5-6)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, 1982 December (Offsite-box 2774, Folder 7-8)
  - Yankelovich: Survey: Results, 1983 March (Offsite-box 2774, Folder 9-10)